Well, but this is a big
deal because potassium
is bigger than sodium.
And so if I am able to on
the surface, let's say,
put something bigger
in there, then you
can imagine that it's
pushing the other stuff
into each other.
That's causing the same stress.
K+ plus bigger than sodium, and
this causes this huge surface
tension.
Same principle as tempering,
but now I've done it chemically.
This is Gorilla Glass.
This is all phone screens.
This is what they do because
you can get really, really
hard glass this way.
And if you go back to these
guys, they have a little--
and this is just a
very short video.
They've got this sort of longer
videos on the Corning website
that talk about this,
and they shoot bullets
through Gorilla Glass.
You can make glass
really strong with just
chemical substitutions, and
all you're thinking about
is atom size.
Because by putting
this larger atom in,
you cause this same kind
of compressive stress
at the surface.
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
- Gorilla Glass, it's
been refined over time,
but like all Gorilla Glass
variants that came before it,
it is compressive-strength
glass.
But it's not made in the same
way as we just demonstrated,
the rapid-cooling method.
No, instead Corning uses
an ion-exchange process.
To break it down
simply, the surface ion
particles that naturally
form during the manufacture
are replaced with
larger ion particles.
Once exchanged, the
larger ion particles
create the same sort
of inward pressure
that we see on the
Prince Rupert drop.
And with this method they are
able to control and manage
the resulting--
[END PLAYBACK]